The young Britannian Lelouch
possesses two powers.
ブリタニアの少年 ルルーシュは
力を２つ持っている
One of them is Geass,
１つはギアス
the absolute power to compel
anyone to do anything.
いかなる相手にでも命令を下せる
絶対遵守の力
And the other is the Black Knights,
１つは黒の騎士団
the military force
he has assembled...
父が統治するブリタニア帝国を
破壊する為の彼の軍隊
in order to destroy the Britannian
Empire ruled by his father.
Using the code name of Zero,
Lelouch has made his move,
ゼロというコードネームを使い
ルルーシュは動き出す
母の仇を討つ為に
seeking to avenge
the death of his mother...
and also to create a world in which his
younger sister Nunnally can be happy.
そして妹 ナナリーが
幸せに過ごせる場所を作る為に
その行動が
いかなる結果を生んでいくのか？
What will be the outcome
of these actions?
At this time, nobody knows yet.
今はまだ 誰も知らない
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間は 何時も直ぐ傍に…
Itsumo sugu soba ni
It's always right there at my side
Kakusenu iradachi to
Even as I stood still, looking at myself
隠せぬ苛立ちと
立ち尽くす自分を 見つめ
Tachitsukusu jibun wo mitsume
With undisguised frustration
Mayoi nagara nayami nagara
Feeling lost, feeling anguished
迷いながら 悩みながら
悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
Kuyami nagara kimereba ii sa
Feeling mournful, deciding what to do
Kimi ga kureta kotoba hitotsu
All it took was a single word from you
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ
Tomadoi wa kiesari
And my uncertainty vanished
戸惑いは消え去り
Karappo datta boku no heya ni hikari ga sashita
You let the light shine into what was my empty room
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
Miageta oozora ga
The sky I had been looking up at...
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
Aoku sumikitte yuku
Cleared and turned blue
Tozashita madowo hiraku
And I decided to throw open...
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を決めた
Koto kimeta
The windows that were kept closed
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間を 感じる今ここに…
Kanjiru ima koko ni
I feel it right here with me
REFRAIN
河口湖の
コンベンションセンターホテルでは
And it looks like they're finally
beginning to get things cleaned up...
ようやく撤去作業が始まるようですね
at the Lake Kawaguchi
convention center hotel.
ゼロが黒の騎士団を宣言してから
２週間以上
It's been over two weeks since Zero
announced the existence of the Black Knights,
結局 確たる証拠は
見つからないままですか
and yet they still haven't found
any definite evidence on him.
逃走ルートは絞り込めたのでは？
Didn't they track his escape route?
んっん… ん
After the release of the hostages,
they escaped using a rail line on the opposite shore.
はあ！
あ…
あっ あ…
あっ カレン！
Kallen...
I mean, Young Mistress.
あっ お嬢様
すみません　起こしてしまって
Forgive me for awakening you.
また？
Again?
すみません
今度は脚立が倒れてしまって
I'm sorry.
This time, the step ladder broke.
早く片付けて
Clean it up at once!
I have to leave for school soon!
もうすぐ学校に行く時間なんだから
お嬢様 最近よく学校に行かれますね
You've been attending school a lot, lately.
Have you made any friends?
お友達とか…
あなたには関係ないでしょ
That's hardly any
of your business!
消えてよ　もう…
Just go away... Please!
I know it's welfare, but it seems like
a waste to give it to the Elevens.
福祉とはいえ イレヴンに
くれてやるには惜しいですなあ
だから そちらに流しているのだろう
Which is why I'm
selling it to you, right?
何 イレヴンは少し減った方が良いのだ
Who cares? It'll be better to cut
down the Eleven population a little.
報酬は奥様の口座の方に
I'll transfer your payment
to your wife's account.
コーネリア殿下は武人だ
Princess Cornelia is a soldier.
こうした事には疎くていらっしゃる
This sort of thing
doesn't interest her.
うん？
おおっ！
うわあ！
灯りだ　灯りを！
Light! Turn on the lights!
What's going on?!
うはっ は…
うおっ！
あっ お前は！
Y-You're!
黒の騎士団！
The Black Knights!
ええ？
わはははっ
ああ？
Um...
ははははっ
あ…
珍しいね　カレンが居眠りなんて
That's not like you,
sleeping in class like that!
う うん　ちょっとね
Well, you know...
ルルーシュに弟子入りしたら？
Why not take some
lessons from Lelouch?
あいつ居眠りは達人だからさ
He's an expert at
sleeping in class.
え？
あれ 眠ってるの？
He's asleep right now?
毎晩 何してるのか知らないけどさ
I dunno what he's up to, night after night,
but he sleeps through half his classes now!
授業の半分は寝てるよ　あいつ
あ…
エルアラメイン戦線では
ＥＵが攻勢に出ている
The E.U.'s starting an offensive
along the El Alamein front.
我々としては
We can't drag our feet
here in Area 11 forever.
いつまでも このエリア11に
足止めされている訳にはいかん
内政を固めて衛星エリアに昇格させたい
I want to solidify domestic affairs and then
promote this place to a satellite Area.
その為にもテロ組織の撲滅は急務だが
For that, not only is wiping out
terrorist organizations a priority,
イレヴンの間に まん延している薬物
リフレインの問題も深刻だ
but the rampant abuse
of the drug Refrain...
among the Elevens
is also a serious problem.
おかげで生産性が落ちている
It's caused a serious
drop in productivity.
ここで中華連邦のキュウシュウルートを
叩いて おかねばならん
We have to stamp out the Chinese Federation's
Kyushu drug route here, understand?
分かるな？
はい　お気をつけて
Yes. Be careful.
お前こそ もう租界からは出るなよ
And you, don't leave the settlement, okay?
お姉様 黒の騎士団の事は…
Sister, about the Black Knights...
もう少し泳がせてやるさ
I'll let them swim free a bit longer.
お前を救ってもらった借りもある
I owe them that much for saving you.
だが 戻って来たら…
But once I return...
ふ…
このエリアは私が きれいにして
お前に渡す
Once I've cleaned up this area, I'll give it to you.
So don't think about these dangerous things.
だから危ない事は考えるな
な ユフィ
All right, Euphy?
あ…
あの男がブリタニア皇帝の子供だから
Because he was a child
of the Britannian emperor.
え？
そういえば あなたも そうでしたね
That reminds me...
You're also one of his children, aren't you?
しかし 今は…
But right now...
あの時 ゼロが話した意味は
まだ続きがある という事かしら？
When he was talking to me...
Was there more to what Zero had to say?
スザク　あなたなら どう思うの？
Suzaku, what would you think about it?
ゼロの行いを
About what Zero is doing.
And about me...
そして 私は…
ふわあ あーあー
さすがにキツいなあ　二重生活は
Man, living a double-life
sure is tough.
ほら スザク　そっち そっち！
C'mon, Suzaku! Hold him down!
バカ やめろ！　スザク！
Dammit, Suzaku! Cut it out!
んん？
やめろ やめるんだ！
Stop it! I demand that you stop!
ごめん ルルーシュ　会長命令だから
Sorry, Lelouch, it's the president's orders.
顔が笑ってるだろ！　おい！
I see you laughing at me!
動かないの！
Quit moving!
うん？
おはようニャン
Morning, meow!
おは… ようございます
Good... morning.
あ！
何 これは？
What's this?
あれ 言ってなかったっけ？
Didn't we mention this?
アーサーの歓迎会
It's our welcome party for Arthur.
平和ですね
It's so peaceful here...
うふっ モラトリアムできるうちは
楽しんでこうよ！
Enjoy life while
we're still free to do it!
We've got your stuff ready,
Kallen. Look.
カレンの分 用意しといたから　ほらっ
この前 変な事言っちゃった お詫び
To make up for all that weird stuff I
said before. Which would you like?
どれにする？
えっ 私も？
What? Me, too?!
カレンはいらないだろ？
Kallen doesn't need one.
えっ
とっくに被ってるもんな？
You already wear a mask.
んっ
あなたテレビにでも出れば？
人気者になれるわよ
Why don't you go on TV?
I'd bet you'd be popular.
どうですか？　テレビスターさん
What do you think, Miss TV Star?
あっ そっちに振るんだ
Yeah, she'd know best.
あ… そういう冗談やめてよ！
Would you quit joking about that?!
あのあと 大変だったんだから
It's been a huge pain
in the ass since all that!
四六時中 追いかけ回されて質問攻め
We get followed around day and
night with people asking questions!
お風呂の中までよ！
Even in the bath, too!
ここ１週間
学校の外に出られなかったしねえ
We haven't been able to
leave the school in a week.
だからって なんで俺達まで
外出禁止なんですか？
I don't see why that means we
can't leave the school, too!
うん　友情ってやつでしょ？
Hmpf! That's the price of friendship!
我ら生まれた時は違えども
死すべき時は同じと願わん
"We ask not the same day of birth,
but we seek to die together.
From 'The Romance of the Three Kingdoms'."
Ｂｙ 三国志
それってプロポーズ？
Is that a proposal?
死にゃば もろともってこった
It's me saying We die together.
ひっでえな　なあスザク　あ？
Man, she's mean!
Don't you think so, Suzaku?
良かった
I'm glad.
へっ？
また みんなで集まれて　本当 良かった
I'm just glad we could all
be together again like this.
ふ…
おおっ！
なんだよ ここは笑うとこなの！
What's with you! This place is for laughing, right?!
ああっ！
あ…
はっ ははははっ
でも そこがスザク君のいいとこよね
Still, that's what we like about Suzaku.
まあ たまに空気読めえって
言いたくなるけどね
Although sometimes
we wish he'd get a clue.
あはっ すみまへん
S-Sowwy 'bowt dat!
お前 それネタだろ
You think it's funny?
うふふふふ
あはははは
そっか
あたし みんなを助けたんだ
That's right.
I helped to save everyone.
ホテルジャック事件での
華々しい登場以来
Ever since our spectacular
introduction at the hoteljacking,
世間は黒の騎士団 一色に染まった
the Black Knights have
taken the world by storm.
黒の騎士団はゼロの宣言通り
弱者の味方だった
Just as Zero had
said in his proclamation,
the Black Knights have been
the allies of the weak.
民間人を巻き込むテロ
Terrorists who involve civilians,
abusive soldiers, and even corrupt politicians.
横暴な軍隊 さらには汚職政治家
営利主義の企業 犯罪組織など
Greedy corporations
and criminal syndicates.
法では裁けない悪を
一方的に断罪していった
Evil which wasn't judged
by the law was punished by us.
私達は あっという間に英雄になった
In the blink of an eye,
we'd become heroes.
協力者も増え
Our supporters have swelled and we've
even gotten some Knightmares again.
ナイトメアまで
再び手に入れる事ができた
もちろん 表立っての話ではない
Of course, this wasn't something people
admitted to publicly, because...
うふふ…
だって…
やめなさい　黒の騎士団なんて…
Stop pretending you're a Black Knight!
なんでだよ
Why?!
We mustn't say anything against Britannia!
We're Elevens, remember?!
ブリタニアの事
悪く言っちゃいけません
私達はイレヴンなのよ
リーダーのゼロは
クロヴィス皇子を殺しているのだから
It was because our leader
Zero had killed Prince Clovis.
仲間うちでも
彼の素顔を知りたがる人は多い
And there are many among our comrades
who want to know who he really is.
私だって そうだ
Myself included.
でも 無理強いすれば
彼はいなくなってしまう気がする
But I have a feeling that, if we
pushed too hard, he'd disappear.
もう彼がいないと
ダメなのかもしれない　私達は
And without him,
I think we'd be powerless.
最近さあ…
You know, lately...
I've hardly seen you.
付き合い悪くない？
そうかな？
Really?
そうだよ
Really.
Are you all right?
あなた 大丈夫？
あ…
ユーフェミアを助けた奴らに
民衆は なぜ協力する？
Why would the masses
help those who saved Euphemia?
キョウトまで黒の騎士団に
紅蓮弐式を回すと言ってきた
Even Kyoto has said they would send
the Black Knights the Guren Mk-II.
あんな義賊気取りに？
To those would-be Robin Hoods?
奴らはレジスタンスじゃない
その証拠に草壁中佐を殺している
They're not part of the resistance!
Their killing Lt. Col. Kusakabe was proof of that!
中佐は自決されたのだろ？
The colonel killed himself, didn't he?
止めなかったという噂もある
There are also rumors
that they didn't try to stop him.
藤堂中佐 いずれにしろ このままでは
In any case, Lt. Col. Tohdoh,
we can't let things stand.
カレンお嬢様 カレンお嬢様
Mistress Kallen! Mistress Kallen!
会長
Ms. President?
ちょっと渡したい物があってね
I just wanted to
give you something.
え？
どちらにお通ししましょうか？
Where shall I show her to?
The parlor, or perhaps the...
客間か それとも…
私の部屋に
To my room.
かしこまりました
As you wish.
あら
Oh. When I heard it was a friend,
I was positive it'd be a boy.
はっ
お友達っていうから
てっきり男だと思ったら…
朝帰りに不登校
ゲットーにも出入りしてるようね
You come home in the
morning and miss school,
not to mention going
out to the ghettos, too.
お父様が本国にいるのを いい事に
You're lucky your father
is back in the homeland.
血は争えないわね
There's no fighting
one's blood, is there?
あ…
父の留守を楽しんでいるのは
あなたの方でしょ！
You're the one enjoying
Dad's absence, aren't you?!
ん…
あっ！
ああ… どうしましょ どうしましょう
Oh, dear! What have I done?
What have I done?!
何やってるの！　あなたは！
What is wrong with you?!
Forgive me, milady! Forgive me!
すみません
奥様 すみません
本当に使えないわね
Honestly, you're useless!
女を売るしか能がなくて
Only thing you're good
at is selling your body!
なかなか複雑な家庭みたいねえ
You have quite a complicated
home life, don't you?
渡したい物って なんですか？
What did you
want to give me?
うーん お爺ちゃんに頼まれてね
Oh, my granddad asked
me to give you this.
学園長に？
The school principal?
中学からの成績証明書
Your school transcripts
since middle school.
あっ
学校で渡さない方が いいと思ったから
I thought it'd be best not
to give them to you at school.
バレたって事ですね
So, you know my secret, then.
私がブリタニア人と
イレヴンのハーフだって事
That I'm a Britannian-Eleven half-breed.
さっきのは継母です
That woman before was my stepmother.
本当の母親は
花瓶を倒したドジなメイドの方
My real mother was that idiot maid
who knocked over the vase.
父親は…
シュタットフェルト家のご当主様？
Your father...
Is he the head of the Stadtfeld family?
バカなんです　母は
My mother's such a fool.
結局 使用人扱いで
In the end, she's just
treated as a servant.
大して仕事もできないから
She can't do any important jobs,
どんなにバカにされても
へらへら笑ってる事しかできなくて
and no matter how they insult her,
all she can do is laugh like it's nothing.
わざわざ この家に住まなくたって
いいのに
She didn't have to specifically
work in this house, did she?
要するに すがってるんですよ 昔の男に
Basically, she's just
hanging on to her old lover!
嫌いなんだ　お母さん
You hate your mother?
うっとうしいだけです
She just depresses me.
ま ヘビーな話よね
My, this conversation
has turned so heavy!
正妻も めかけも その娘も
一緒に暮らしてるなんて
Imagine, the wife, the daughter,
and the "other woman," all living together.
そうでも ないですよ
No, it's not like that.
衣食住に不自由はないし
We can all have a
decent life here for free.
我慢できないってほどじゃ
ありませんから
The situation isn't quite... unbearable.
そう？
Oh?
でもね
Still, while some things
you can bear on their own,
ひとつひとつは我慢できる事でも
積み重なれば
いつか擦り切れてしまうものよ
when you pile them all up,
they eventually break you.
はっ
大丈夫
Relax. I know I like to
know peoples' secrets,
人の秘密って知りたくなる方だけど
話す趣味はないから
but I have no interest
in telling anyone about this.
ううう…
あああ…
あ…
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
あんな所で泣くなよな
Crying, like you were before...
How embarrassing!
恥ずかしい奴
Call it me being honest.
素直って言ってよ
ううっ！
ま みんなが助かったのは
良かったけどな
Well, it was a good thing everyone was
saved. Thanks to the Black Knights.
黒の騎士団さまさまだ
あ…
犯罪者を取り締まりたいなら
警察に入れば いいのに
If they wanted to catch criminals,
they could have joined the police.
彼らはどうして そうしないんだろう？
Why don't they do that?
警察じゃできないと思ったんだろう
警察なんて…
Probably because they don't think
the police can do it. Cops... Right!
The police may not be effective now,
but they could change them from within!
今はダメでも 警察の中に入って
変えていけば いいじゃないか
変える過程で
結局は色々なしがらみを抱える事になる
And in the process of changing it,
they end up tangled in all sorts of restrictions.
それは
They only get to say that after they
at least make the effort to change it!
ぎりぎりまで変える努力をしてから
初めて言える事だよ
それをしない限り 彼らの言い分は
独善に過ぎない
As long as they don't,
all their talk is just being self-righteous!
独善？
Self-righteous?
彼らが言う悪ってなんだい？
And what exactly
are they declaring wrong?
何を基準にしているのかも
分からないじゃないか
We don't know what
standard they base that on!
一方通行の自己満足だよ
It's just one-sided self-satisfaction!
あ！
あれ ２人だけ？
Oh? Just you two?
それじゃあ
僕は軍に戻らなくちゃ ならないから
Well then, I've got to go back
to the base. See you, Shirley.
じゃあね　シャーリー
あ… うん…
ふふっ じゃあね
See you!
ふん
うん
ねえ ルル
So, Lulu! I was wondering...
今度… さあ…
時間が合えば… で いいんだけど
私と…
I was wondering,
if you had the time, maybe we could...
あいつ 軍に戻らなくちゃって
言ったよな
He said he had
to go back to the base.
えっ
戻る…
Go back... Implying that's where he thinks he belongs.
そこが お前の居場所って事か
リフレイン？
Refrain?
麻薬
It's a narcotic. Specifically, it makes you
feel like you've gone back to the past.
過去に戻った気になるってのが
特徴かな？
売れそうですね　特に日本人に
Sounds like a hot seller,
especially to Japanese people.
誰だって懐かしいよ
Everyone gets nostalgic for the days
before Britannia occupied Japan.
ブリタニアに占領される前の日本が
ん…
日本人を狙い撃ちにした薬だ
It's a drug specifically
targeted at the Japanese.
放っては おけないだろう
We can't just ignore it.
無頼の補充物資が届いたら すぐに動く
We'll move as soon as
we get the Burais resupplied.
補給も増えたし
We're getting more supplies and I
hear lots of people want to join us.
仲間になりたい人も
いっぱいいるって聞きました
黒の騎士団は人気者ですね
The Black Knights are popular, aren't they?
正義の味方だからな
Well, we are knights of justice.
弾薬が届いたら また連絡する
I'll contact you again
once the ammunition arrives.
なんとか言ってみろよ！　イレヴンが！
C'mon, Eleven! Say something!
ん？
C'mon, apologize! Apologize!
謝罪しろ
謝罪
イレヴンは頭下げんのが
得意だろうが！
Bowing your heads is what you Elevens do best, right?!
イレヴン… んっ
Eleven...
は！
ルルーシュ！
Lelouch!
相手は５人だ
There're five of them.
You'd never win.
勝てる訳ないだろ？
だからって放っておけるの？
So I should just ignore it?!
Look carefully at the
Eleven they're beating up.
よく見ろ　やられてるイレヴンを
は？
いいっ… んっ
下手に加勢して あいつらに勝ってみろ
Suppose we help him
and he manages to win.
あのイレヴンは
明日から ここで商売ができなくなる
Starting tomorrow,
he wouldn't be able to sell anything here.
あいつは自分で
ブリタニアの奴隷を選んだんだ
He decided on his own
to be a slave to the Britannians.
租界で働くってのは そういう事だろ？
That's the price for
working in the settlement.
だからって！
Even so!
You got a problem over there?
文句あんの？　そっち
イレヴンが かわいそうだってか？
Feeling sorry for that Eleven?
Nah, they want to
join in, don't they?
違うって 仲間に入りたいんだよ　な？
まさか
Hardly.
あんたらも もう飽きたんだろ？
But you're tired of bullying
Elevens now, aren't you?
イレヴンいじめなんて
あーあ つまんねえの
Yeah, this sucks.
ゲーセンでも行く？
Wanna go to the arcade?
へっ 金ねえよ
I got no cash!
ん…
飽きっぽい連中だな
Easily bored, aren't they?
う… うっう…
大丈夫？
Are you all right?
うう…
ああっ
あっ ブリタニアの学生さん
A Britannian student!
い いらっしゃいませ
Wh-What can I get for you?
How about a nice California Dog?
うっ カリフォルニアドックは
いかがですか？
え？
ああ！
恋人さんですか？
Is this your boyfriend?!
I'd be glad to get something for him, too!
良かったら お２人でどうぞ！
アイスクリームもありますよ
I have ice cream, if you like.
エリア11は日本だった頃に比べて
良くなった とも言えるよ
In a way, Area 11 is better
compared with the old Japan.
ブリタニアの植民エリアに
入れたおかげで
Thanks to its being brought into
the Britannian colonization areas,
軍事も経済も格段に安定した
its military and economic affairs
have become markedly more stable.
市民権だって手に入る
Elevens can even
get full citizenship.
If they follow the right legal procedures,
they can become honorary Britannians, can't they?
役所に行って手続きをすれば
名誉ブリタニア人に なれるじゃないか
あとはプライドの問題
Beyond that,
it's just a question of pride.
ま そっちを大事にしたい気持ちも
分かるけどね
Well, I can understand
why they'd value that feeling.
それで？
And?
ん？
Hm?
そこまで分かってて
Knowing all that,
ルルーシュ・ランペルージは
どういう考えなの？
what does Lelouch Lamperouge think
about it? What do you want to do?
何をしたいの？
別に
Nothing, really.
君は随分 頭がいいみたいだけど
持ち腐れね
You know, you seem smart,
but you don't use your brains.
シャーリーが嘆いてたわ
Shirley's always sighing about that.
ルルは努力しようとしない
せっかく頭がいいのにって
She says you're so smart,
but never make an effort at anything.
だから何もしないんだろ
That's why I don't do anything.
あ…
さっきのイレヴンだって分かってるんだ
Even that Eleven we saw
before would understand.
ブリタニア人に頭を下げた方が
いい暮らしが できるって
How he can live a better life as long as
he keeps bowing to the Britannians.
えっ？
えいっ！
うっ う…
かっこいいと思ってるの？
You think you're so
damned cool, don't you?!
そんな評論家ぶって
世間を ななめに見てるのが！
Just playing critic as you
view the world from the side?!
ふ…
少しでも期待した私がバカだったわ
I was a fool to expect
anything more from you.
多少は マシな男だと思ったのに
I thought you were
a better man than this!
ふん
ああ…
例のオレンジ事件の…
About that Orange thing from before.
だっ
失礼しました
Sorry to bring it up.
Is it true you can't remember anything about
when Suzaku Kururugi was taken from us?
例の枢木スザク強奪事件の時の
卿の記憶がない というのは
本当でしょうか？
I don't expect you to believe me.
信じてもらおうとは思わん
いえ
No, it's just... During the Shinjuku incident,
実は私もシンジュク事変の時に
記憶の喪失を経験しているのです
I also got a blank in my memory.
何？
What?
意識が戻った時には
サザーランドを奪われていました
When I regained my senses,
my Sutherland had been stolen.
But right before the hole in my memory,
I recall running into a boy wearing a student uniform.
それに記憶を失う直前
私は学生服の少年と会っているのです
では その学生が？
You think the student did it?
I can't remember his face,
but it may be worth checking into.
顔は思い出せません
しかし 調べてみる価値はあるかと
何 考えてんだ　ゼロの奴は
What the hell is
that Zero guy thinking?!
After all that talk about
bringing down Britannia,
ブリタニアを倒すって言ってたくせに
やってる事は警察の手伝いじゃねえか
all we do now
is help the cops out!
でも人に感謝されるのって
悪い気分じゃないよ
Still, it doesn't feel bad having
people being grateful to us.
そうそう ネットじゃ英雄だもんな
Yeah, yeah.
We're heroes on the Net, you know.
けっ
私達さあ これで良いんだよね？
We're doing the right thing, aren't we?
カレン
Kallen...
ゼロからの合図だ
There's the signal from Zero!
よく入れたな
How'd he get in?
毎回 毎回 どんな手品使ってやがんだ
Using whatever trick
he always uses.
ナゴヤの分は終わったのか？
You finished packing
the stuff for Nagoya?
It's so safe here inside
the settlement, huh?
安全だよ　租界の中は
うわあ！
どわあ！
どりゃっ
The Black Knights have arrived!
黒の騎士団 参上！
侵入者だあ！
Intruders!
ナイトメア！
A Knightmare!
そんな！
Aw, hell no!
冗談じゃないぞ！
Are you kidding me?!
うわあ！
うわあー
These Knightmares really are amazing.
Even one is practically unstoppable!
やっぱりナイトメアはすごい！
１機あるだけで圧倒的
あっ
Japan! Japan!
日本！　日本！
はい 来月 結婚するんです！
Yes! I'm getting married next month!
栄転だぞ！　今度はパリ支店だって
I've been promoted!
I'm going to the Paris office!
You'll go with me to see the
fireworks next week, won't you?!
来週の花火 一緒に行くよね？
Leave it to me! Japan's technology
is the best in the world, isn't it?!
任せて下さい
日本の技術は世界一ですから！
リフレイン
Refrain...
決まったんだよ！　留学
やるぞー 俺は！
It's all set!
I'm studying abroad! I did it!
う…
When you pile them all up,
they eventually break you.
積み重なれば
いつか擦り切れてしまうものよ
そうよ　だから私は！
That's right, which is why I'm!
Careful! Careful!
It's dangerous to run like that!
ほらほら 走ったら危ないわよ
あ…
お母さん？
Mother?!
ああっ
あっ！
Naoto, really!
You have to keep an eye on Kallen!
こらナオト！　ちゃんとカレンの事
見ててあげなきゃダメでしょ
あなたって女は どれだけ弱いの
How weak a woman are you?!
ブリタニアにすがって 男にすがって
You gave in to the Britannians,
to a man, now to drugs?!
今度は薬！
お兄ちゃんは もういないんだよ
これ以上！
Big brother's gone! Just stop this!
ああっ！
え？
ナイトポリス？
A Knight police?!
あれ警察のだろ？
Isn't that a police unit?!
Working with them?! Tamaki!
グルって事か？　玉城！
知らねえよ！　俺が調べた時は確かに…
I dunno! When I checked things out,
I was sure that...
腐ってやがる
So corrupt!
うっ
うっ 邪魔だ！
You're in the way!
どうして…
Why?! I don't want you, but!
いらないのに…
いらないのに！
I don't want you, but!
ううっ あっ
カレン… ナオト
Kallen... Naoto...
はっ
うわあー！
Against a Knightmare!
ナイトメア相手では…
にげ… ろ…
Run for it...
Run, you idiot!
逃げろ！　このバカ！
いるから
I'm here for you.
はっ
ずっと 傍にいるから…
カレン　傍にいるからね
I'm here for you.
Kallen, I'll always be here for you!
はっ あ…
だから…
That's why... That's why you
stayed working in that house?!
だから…
あんなうちに居続けたっていうの？
For that?! Oh, you idiot!
そんな事の為に バカじゃないの！
うっ！
バカは…
The real idiot... was me.
あたしだ　ううっ！
カレン！
Kallen!
う… くっ
はっ
I'm so happy for you, Kallen.
You can be a Britannian now.
良かったね　カレン
おまえはブリタニア人になれるんだよ
そうなれば もう殴られる事もない
Now no one will ever hurt you.
電話だって旅行だって
自由にできるんだよ
You're free to use the
phone and even travel.
That was... her mother?
母親… だったのか
嘘の涙は人を傷つける
False tears bring pain to others.
嘘の笑顔は自分を…
A false smile brings pain to yourself.
It's an aftereffect of the drug.
She can't talk much.
薬の後遺症です
会話は ほとんどできません
回復するとしても 時間が必要かと…
She'll recover eventually,
but she needs time.
判決 出たよ　20年だって
They sentenced you. 20 years...
待ってて
Just wait! I'll try to change it
all for when you come back!
お母さんが出てくるまでには
変えてみせるから
あたしとお母さんが
普通に暮らせる世界に
I'll make a world where you and
I can live together normally...
だから だから… うっ…
So, please... Please!
はっ
頑張れ
Hang in there...
え？
頑張れカレン　私の娘
Hang in there, Kallen...
My daughter...
あっ は…
うふっ… うん 頑張る
I will!
あたし 頑張るから
I'll do my best!
うふっ…
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと吠え
Yukedomo kemonomichi
Walking along the animal path
Shishi yotorayoto hoe
Roaring with the lions and tigers
茜射す空の 彼方にまほろば
Akane sasu sora no kanata ni mahoroba
Paradise lying far across a sky dyed red
幽囚の孤獨に 彷徨う青春は
Yuushuu no kodoku ni samayou seishun wa
To a youth wandering, imprisoned in loneliness
弱さと怒りが姿無き敵ですか
Yowasato ikari ga sugata naki teki desu ka
Are weakness and hatred shapeless enemies?
父よ 未だ我は
Chichi yo madaware wa
Oh father, I am still...
己を知りがたし
Onore wo shirigatashi
Learning who I am
先立つ兄らの
Sakidatsu anira no
As I pursue the backs I no longer see
見えない背中を追えば
Mienai senakawo oeba
Of the elder brothers who have gone before me
迷いの一夜に明星は誘う
Mayoi no hitoyo ni
In the night I spend lost
Myoujou wa izanau
The morning star beckons to me
死して終わらぬ
Shi shite owaranu
This will not end in my death
夢を焦がれども
Yume wo kogaredomo
I long for my dream
確かな君こそ我が命
Tashika na kimi kosowaga inochi
My faith in you sustains my life
Reppu no kouya de
In the windswept wilderness
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Chou yo hanayoto iki
Living with the butterflies and flowers
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
Tokoshie no haru ni sakisou maboroshi
Blooming together in a mirage of eternal Spring
混獨の純潔 この身は汚れても
Kondaku nojunketsu
If my purity seems muddied
Kono mi wayogoretemo
And my body seems filthy
心の錦を信じていてください
Kokoro no nishiki wo shinjiteite kudasai
Please believe in the finery within my heart
母よ けして我は
Hahayo kesshite ware wa namidawo misene domo
Oh mother, I will show no tears
涙を見せねども
足下の草に露は消えもせで
Ashimoto no
They vanish like...
Kusa ni tsuyu wa kiemosede
The dew in the grass beneath my feet
過去の思い出？
Memories of the past?
そんなものに浸れる奴は幸せだ
Those who can indulge
in them are happy.
明日が必ず来ると思っているのだから
Because they believe that
tomorrow will definitely come.
しかし
それは誰が約束したものなのか？
But who promised that?
カレンがそれを
乗り越えようとしているのなら
If Kallen is trying to move beyond that,
then it's right to believe in her.
信じてもいい
そう
That's right.
All we can do is live for the moment.
俺達は今を生きるしかないのだから